<Opcode name="PCM_OP_SUBSCRIPTION_SET_PRODINFO" visibility="public"
        transaction="required" component="fm_subscription"
        xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.portal.com/schemas/BusinessOpcodes opspec.xsd"
        xmlns="http://www.portal.com/schemas/BusinessOpcodes">
 <Doc>
  PCM_OP_SUBSCRIPTION_SET_PRODINFO input and output flist specifications. This
  opcode is called to modify or set a product's purchase, cycle, or usage date
  information. If the PCM_OPFLG_CALC_ONLY flag is set, this opcode returns the 
  entire event flist for the events created as a result of the modification. 
  If not, it returns the event POIDs of all event objects created as a result 
  of the modification.
  <h:p/>
  <h:p/>
  When automatic rerating is enabled, this opcode triggers automatic rerating of
  backdated product status changes when certain conditions are met.
 </Doc>
 <!-- INPUT SPEC -->
 <Input>
  <Fields>
   <Poid name="PIN_FLD_POID" use="required" mode="complete">
    <Doc>Account object action was applied to.</Doc>
    <ClassRef>obj://account</ClassRef>
   </Poid>
   <Poid name="PIN_FLD_SERVICE_OBJ" use="optional" mode="complete">
    <Doc>Service object action was applied to.</Doc>
    <ClassRef>obj://service</ClassRef>
   </Poid>
   <Poid name="PIN_FLD_SESSION_OBJ" use="optional" mode="complete">
    <Doc>Session object - session in which event took place - null means none.</Doc>
    <ClassRef>obj://event.session</ClassRef>
   </Poid>
   <String name="PIN_FLD_PROGRAM_NAME" use="required" maxlen="60">
    <Doc>Program name - identifies calling program.</Doc>
   </String>
   <String name="PIN_FLD_DESCR" use="optional" maxlen="255">
    <Doc>Event description - free text for application to describe event.</Doc>
   </String>
   <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_START_T" use="optional">
    <Doc>Start time - Timestamp of when event started (Portal Time).</Doc>
   </Timestamp>
   <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_END_T" use="optional">
    <Doc>End time - Timestamp of when event ended (Portal Time). This field is
         used to determine which billing cycle the event is part of.</Doc>
   </Timestamp>
   <Int name="PIN_FLD_FLAGS" use="optional">
    <Doc>This flags is used to truncate or extend the sub balance validity of
         non currency resources during Line Transfer. If the value is passed as
         PIN_RATE_FLG_CUT then the sub balance validity is truncated to date of
         transfer and iff the value is passed as PIN_RATE_FLG_MAINTAIN then the
         sub balance validity period is extended till the source account's
         current billing cycle end date and if the value is passed as
         PIN_RATE_FLG_ALIGN then the sub balance bucket is extended till the
         destination account's billing cycle end date.</Doc>
   </Int>
   <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_ACTG_NEXT_T" use="optional">
    <Doc>Accounting Next_T of the destination account used in extending the
         validity period of the sub balance bucket for the products during line
         transfer in case of business params for sub_bal_validity is configured
         to Align.</Doc>
   </Timestamp>
   <Array name="PIN_FLD_PRODUCTS" use="required" elemIdMode="ignored"
          iterationOrder="undefined">
    <Doc>Products array. Only one element can appear in this array. Element-id
         is not relevant. It uniquely identifies the account product by its
         offering_obj.</Doc>
    <Fields>
     <Poid name="PIN_FLD_PRODUCT_OBJ" use="required" mode="complete">
      <Doc>Poid of product to purchase.</Doc>
      <ClassRef>obj://product</ClassRef>
     </Poid>
     <Poid name="PIN_FLD_OFFERING_OBJ" use="required" mode="complete">
      <Doc>Uniquely identifies a product in an account.</Doc>
      <ClassRef>obj://purchased_product</ClassRef>
     </Poid>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_START_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Purchase start time - timestamp that product activates (Portal Time).</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_END_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Purchase end time - timestamp that product expires (Portal Time), 0
           means that product does not expire.</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_END_UNIT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative Unit for Purchase Can be Seconds=1,Minutes=2,Hours=3,Days=4,
           Months=5, Cycles=8 and Event cycles=9. For First Usage unit should be
	   passed as -1. For unit=0, the purchase end_t would be checked.
	   If unit is 0 and purchase end_t is 0 then End Never.
	   If unit is 0 and purchase end_t is greater than 0 then purchase end date 
	   is an Absolute date. Based on this the purchase end details would be 
	   calculated.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_END_OFFSET" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative offset for Purchase startT to be used in conjunction with
           unit to calculate Purchase endT on First Usage.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_DISCOUNT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Purchase discount - percent discount applied to purchase/cancel rates
           of product. Mutually exclusive to PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_DISC_AMT field.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_DISC_AMT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Fixed amount discount for purchase fees, amount of discount applied
           to purchase/cancel rates of product. Mutually exclusive to
	   PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_DISCOUNT field.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_PURCHASE_FEE_AMT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Purchase fee to be applied for this product. Amount specified here
           will override the price specified in the /rate object.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_START_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Cycle fee start time - timestamp that cycle fees begin for this
           product (Portal Time), 0 means immediately. This field should
	   not be changed for an existing product.</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_END_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Cycle fee end time - timestamp that cycle fees are no longer applied
           for this product (Portal Time), 0 means always applied.</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_END_UNIT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative Unit for Cycle Can be Seconds=1, Minutes=2, Hours=3, Days=4,
           Months=5, Cycles=8 and Event cycles=9. For First Usage unit should be
	   passed as -1. For unit=0, the cycle end_t would be checked.
	   If unit is 0 and cycle end_t is 0 then End Never.
	   If unit is 0 and cycle end_t is greater than 0 then cycle end date is
	   an Absolute date. Based on this the cycle end details would be 
	   calculated.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_END_OFFSET" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative offset for Cycle to be used in conjunction with unit to
           calculate Cycle end_t.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_DISCOUNT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Cycle fee discount - percent discount applied to cycle rates of
           product. Mutually exclusive to PIN_FLD_CYCLE_DISC_AMT field.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_DISC_AMT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Fixed amount discount for cycle_forward fees amount of discount
           applied to cycle rates of product. Mutually exclusive to
	   PIN_FLD_CYCLE_DISCOUNT field.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_CYCLE_FEE_AMT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Cycle fee (both forward and arrears) to be applied for this product.
           Amount specified here will override the price specified in the /rate
           object.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_STATUS_FLAGS" use="optional">
     <Doc> Status flags used in conjunction with the override prices specified in <h:a h:href="#in.PRODUCTS.PURCHASE_FEE_AMT">PURCHASE_FEE_AMT</h:a> and <h:a h:href="#in.PRODUCTS.CYCLE_FEE_AMT">CYCLE_FEE_AMT</h:a>. The possible values are: -
       <h:ul>
        <h:li>PIN_PROD_STATUS_FLAGS_OVERRIDE_PURCHASE_FEE(0x01000000) </h:li>
        <h:li>PIN_PROD_STATUS_FLAGS_OVERRIDE_CYCLE_FEE(0x02000000)</h:li>
       </h:ul>
    </Doc>
    </Int>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_USAGE_START_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Usage fee start time - timestamp that usage fees begin for this
           product (Portal Time), 0 means immediately.</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Timestamp name="PIN_FLD_USAGE_END_T" use="optional">
      <Doc>Usage fee end time - timestapm that usage fees are no longer applied
           for this product (Portal Time), 0 means always applied.</Doc>
     </Timestamp>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_USAGE_END_UNIT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative Unit for Usage Can be Seconds=1, Minutes=2, Hours=3, Days=4,
           Months=5, Cycles=8 and Event cycles=9. For First Usage unit should be
	   passed as -1. For unit=0, the usage end_t would be checked.
	   If unit is 0 and usage end_t is 0 then End Never.
	   If unit is 0 and usage end_t is greater than 0 then usage end date is
	   an Absolute date. Based on this the usage end details would be 
	   calculated.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Int name="PIN_FLD_USAGE_END_OFFSET" use="optional">
      <Doc>Relative offset for Usage to be used in conjunction with unit to
           calculate Usage end_t on First Usage.</Doc>
     </Int>
     <Decimal name="PIN_FLD_USAGE_DISCOUNT" use="optional">
      <Doc>Usage fee discount - percent discount applied to usage rates of
           product.</Doc>
     </Decimal>
     <String name="PIN_FLD_DESCR" use="optional" maxlen="255">
      <Doc>Description on a per product basis for CSR to add comments.</Doc>
     </String>
     <String name="PIN_FLD_PRICE_LIST_NAME" use="optional" maxlen="255">
      <Doc>Price list name associated with this offering.</Doc>
     </String>     
    </Fields>
   </Array>
  </Fields>
 </Input>
 <!-- OUTPUT SPEC -->
 <Output>
  <Fields>
   <Poid name="PIN_FLD_POID" use="required" mode="complete">
    <Doc>Account object passed into call.</Doc>
    <ClassRef>obj://account</ClassRef>
   </Poid>
   <Array name="PIN_FLD_RESULTS" use="optional" elemIdMode="ignored"
          iterationOrder="undefined">
    <Doc>Array of results information. Since only one event object is created by
         this call, only one element will be returned. The element-id is not
         significant.</Doc>
    <Fields>
     <Poid name="PIN_FLD_ACCOUNT_OBJ" use="optional" mode="complete">
       <Doc>Poid of the account object.</Doc>
       <ClassRef>obj://account</ClassRef>
     </Poid>
     <Poid name="PIN_FLD_POID" use="required" mode="complete">
      <Doc>Poid of the event object created for event</Doc>
     </Poid>
     <Any name="EVT_FLDS" use="optional" mode="other" baseClassName="obj://event"
      classNameRef="#out.RESULTS.POID">
      <Doc> Fields of the event object. Additional event object fields are added
        to the return flist here. If the PCM_OPFLG_READ_RESULT flag is set for 
        the operation, all the fields in the event object are returned on the 
        output flist, not just the POID. If the PCM_OPFLG_CALC_ONLY flag is set,
        no fields in the database are changed and the event object is not actually
        created, but the fields that would have been used to create the event 
        object are returned to the caller on the output flist.</Doc>
     </Any>
    </Fields>
   </Array>
  </Fields>
 </Output>
</Opcode>

